# VÍTOR TEIXEIRA

## USER EXPERIENCE PROFESSIONAL

I'm a User Experience Professional with a passion for solving problems with smart and simple user-centered design. Passionate about life and technology, my goal is to make sure the latter does not get in the way of the former, but instead makes it better.

# > WORK EXPERIENCE

SKY STORE
SKY - PORTUGAL
Feb 2016 - Present

### **USER EXPERIENCE ENGINEER**

Bridged communication between Product and UX/UI team in London and Development team in Lisbon.

Designed and tested prototypes with users and stakeholders.

Performed regular heuristic evaluations of Sky Store's range of applications.

Ensured Accessibility, SEO, and Performance guidelines were adopted.

Participated in the adoption of new technologies and frameworks on the Sky Store web client

MAIN PROJECTS: Sky Store Web

SAPO
PORTUGAL TELECOM
Apr 2013 - Jan 2016

#### USER EXPERIENCE & QUALITY ASSURANCE

Conducted the user-centered design process of some of SAPO's main web projects.

Designed and tested wireframes and prototypes with users and stakeholders.

Designed user studies' protocols and questionnaires.

Performed heuristic evaluations of SAPO's and partner's products. Ensured Accessibility, SEO, and Performance guidelines were adopted. Conducted card sorting and usability test sessions with users. Developed and reviewed the results of A/B and Multivariate tests.

MAIN PROJECTS: SAPO Mag | SAPO Biz | SAPO Blogs | SAPO Vídeos | SAPO Promos | SAPO UX

MLDC
MICROSOFT - PORTUGAL
Jan 2011 - Mar 2013

#### SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT ENGINEER / RESEARCHER

Researched on natural user interaction and Human-computer interaction. Interviewed elderly users to gather requirements for the development of a multimodal digital personal assistant.

Specified, prototyped, tested and developed desktop, mobile, and web projects.

Conducted usability studies with users, both elderly and mobility-impaired.

MAIN PROJECTS: Living Usability Lab | AAL4ALL | PaeLife | Living Home Center Prototype

# **EDUCATION**

DEGREE & MASTER OF SCIENCE 2006 - 2011

#### TELECOMMUNICATIONS AND INFORMATION SCIENCE

ISCTE - University Institute of Lisbon (ISCTE-IUL)

Dissertation on the impact, in the elderly population, of multimodal graphical user interfaces for interacting with communication services and social networks.

Dissertation PDF (3.6 MB)

Birth

Phone (+351) 968784447

Email

Website

LinkedIn

inkedin.com/in/vsdteixeira

## Skillset

l Iser research

Wireframir

Prototyping

nformation Architecture

nteraction design

Usability testing

Heuristic evaluation

A/B testing

Front-end development

## Toolkit

Sketch

Omnigraffle

Ator

HTML/CSS/JS

Slack / Skyr

Brain, Pen and Paper

## Hobbies

Talking about UX
Movies & TV Shows
Hardboiled Literature
DiY / Handywork
Barbecuing

# Languages

**PORTUGUESE** 

**ENGLISH** 

SPANISH

